<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Sameer's Blog</title><link>https://sameerahman24.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Sameer's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.140.1</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Sameer Rahman</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sameerahman24.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Web-Controlled ESP32 Microscope: Remote Imaging with M5TimerCamera</title><link>https://sameerahman24.github.io/posts/m5microscope/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sameerahman24.github.io/posts/m5microscope/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I recently got an internship where I was tasked to program a microcontroller, specifically ESP32-based M5TimerCamera. The camera is connected to an external lens and is used as a microscope to display the images taken onto a smartphone device. By joining the WiFi access point of the M5Camera and going to the IP address from the browser, images can be captured by clicking a button. Furthermore, specific settings like exposure and gain values can be changed from the web browser as well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making Pacman way harder than it needs to be</title><link>https://sameerahman24.github.io/posts/pathfinding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sameerahman24.github.io/posts/pathfinding/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I was creating a game inspired from Pacman to brush up my coding skills that I learnt on the first semester of college only to come across a road block. How will the ghosts track the player and move towards you? The solution I used is the &lt;strong>Greedy Best-First Search&lt;/strong>. Now before we dive into it we must first familiarize ourselves with how the ghosts move in the game itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://sameerahman24.github.io/posts/aboutme/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 20:07:49 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://sameerahman24.github.io/posts/aboutme/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-start">The Start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hello, my name is &lt;strong>Sameer&lt;/strong>, and this is the beginning of my new blog. I&amp;rsquo;m currently studying at &lt;strong>Case Western Reserve University&lt;/strong>. I’m enthusiastic about tech and love learning new skills and this blog will be a space where I share my journey, projects, and the latest skills I’ve picked up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feel free to follow along, and if you have any questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to me via email.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tags</title><link>https://sameerahman24.github.io/tags/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sameerahman24.github.io/tags/</guid><description>Browse posts by tags.</description></item></channel></rss>